Hello! How do you feel when you find a
vulnerability
with cool filter bypass? Because I feel
absolutely amazing!
But today i have for you a vulnerability
where four filters were bypassed
to exploit XSS on airbnb website.
The vulnerability was found by Brett
Bauerhaus and Ben Sadeghipour
aka NahamSec. He also has a youtube
channel
full of talks with great bug bounty
hunters.
And my today's video is based on a
write-up from Brett's blog.
The link as always is in the description.
enjoy!
so on embeddable/listing_frame endpoint
on airbnb, data from parameter
city-link-index was reflected inside
the JSON body and the first thing
that you need to know is that there is
script with type
application/json and inside such tag
no javascript code gets executed.
But if you can smuggle a closing script
tag,
even inside the string in the json, the
tag gets closed.
And then you can open another script tag,
this time the normal one and execute
javascript code inside.
But of course it didn't work in this
case, because if it would
I wouldn't make a video about it.
Let's start
with bypassing xss filter
so if you send any HTML tag in the value
of the parameter
it got deleted, but if you would put
a semicolon at the beginning of the
parameter value,
the tag would not be deleted. And one
thing to notice
is that previously the payload was in
the JSON value,
but the semicolon made the parser think
that this value is ended and another key-value pair
is created and likely this is what
confused
the xss filter. And you might be thinking
why are they using a tag instead of a
<script> tag.
The reason is that if you have
multiple filters present,
you want to separate them and bypass
them one by one.
So first you need to see if you can
inject
any HTML code and for that purpose
the least dangerous tags are the best.
So we have bypassed one protection and
we can
close the <script> tag and now it's time
to open another tag
with our javascript code. But this time
web application firewall prevents us.
Now what's the difference between xss
filter
and web application firewall? The former
works inside the application code and
it's only used
in some specific places. Whereas web
application firewall
or WAF is more like a plugin to the
server
which analyzes all the requests.
And it was rather secure because it
prevented the researchers
from using an opening script tag.
The only way it was possible to smuggle
the script tag, was using url encoded
null byte inside it. It got converted,
but it was not a valid HTML script tag.
But luckily javascript code can also be
executed
in other places, for example in
attributes
of another tags. Example of that
is image tag with onerror attribute
that gets triggered.
WAF also blocked function calls, but
luckily
this could be bypassed by inserting
a comment between the function name
and the parenthesis.
So now, it was time to try different HTML
attributes
to execute code. And up to this point
the payload was always in JSON key,
but when an equal sign was sent, then
everything
before it was treated as the JSON key
and everything after
was treated as the value. So the first
attribute would always be ignored by the
browser,
because there would be no equal sign but
using forward slashes as attribute
separators,
it was possible to inject more than one
attribute. But of course the attributes
were also blocked by the firewall. And
the same bypass
that did not work with the script tag,
now
worked with the attributes because the
null bytes were getting discarded
leaving valid attribute names.
So finally we have a way to smuggle
arbitrary attributes so we can send a
classic
image payload and it should work.
But it didn't as there was also content
security policy.
What is it? CSP limits what resources you
can use on the website.
It's additional layer of security that
helps
to mitigate cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities.
You can define domains that you trust
and you only want to execute scripts
from that site.
You can also tell the browser that you
do not trust
any inline scripts on the website and
you do not want browser to
execute them. And on airbnb
the CSP part that's interesting to us
looked like this. And the sha-256
part tells the browser that it can only
execute
scripts that have checksum equal to this
value.
And this includes both standard script
tags,
as well as javascript in the attributes.
And without getting deep into
cryptography
we can say that it's impossible to
create
a script that would have a valid checksum.
And if a script element could be used
it would be possible to find some
bypasses to the content security policy,
but previous attempts have already shown
this
to be a really tall order.
So the xss has to be exploited using
another tag. And at the time of recording
this video,
in 2020, flash is being dropped by modern
browsers,
but back in 2017, when this report was
initially submitted, flash could be
widely used
to exploit XSS or JSON CSRFs.
And using an embed tag it's possible
to use swf file to execute
an actionscript file. This is the code
that was used by the hackers.
i won't go into the detail all that's
important
is that this line executes javascript
code.
And finally the alert popped up,
but the web application firewall
happened out
to be really annoying and the same
payload
sometimes worked and sometimes didn't.
And this is the payload that would work
every single time.
And at this point you might be thinking
what was the process
of getting from one payload to another.
And the truth is
in such case the process is simply trial
and error.
You just have to submit many many
payloads and suddenly
one of them works, because in such
complicated case,
when the same payload one time works and
one time doesn't,
it's impossible to reverse engineer and
understand
what actually gets filtered and what
doesn't.
And this payload only worked in firefox
as in google chrome there was xss
auditor,
which is also dropped in 2020.
And after another series of payloads
sent to the server this is what worked
both in chrome and firefox
every single time. And as the site relied
on those protections the researchers
managed to find
seven more occurrences of this xss
including store ones, which of course
have bigger impact.
The exact amount of bounty rewarded for
this report
is not known. Back then airbnb paid five
thousand dollars
for simple stored xss and a little less
for reflected one.
Here, in total, we have eight
vulnerabilities,
but they have the same root cause so my
guess the vulnerability was paid
around fifteen thousand dollars and
that's definitely
the best XSS I have ever seen.
If you've enjoyed it as much as i did
or you've liked my explanation leave a
like and a subscription down below
and for now i wish you happy hunting and
goodbye!